mccormick.com 2019-06-10

# Privacy Policy | McCormick

**_Last revised February 18, 2013_**

This site is owned and operated by **McCormick & Company, Incorporated** (“McCormick”). We at McCormick recognize that you are concerned about your personal privacy. 

This Privacy Policy is provided to inform you of what personal information is collected on our websites and how that information is maintained and used by McCormick. This Privacy Policy applies to all information collected or submitted on [www.mccormick.com](https://www.mccormick.com/) and [www.mccormickcorporation.com](https://www.mccormickcorporation.com/). 

This Privacy Policy is current as of the effective date set forth above. McCormick reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy as our practices may change, so we encourage you to review the privacy policy from time to time. 

**Personal Information We Collect.** You don't need to provide any personal information to access our websites. However, McCormick provides you the opportunity to enhance your visit to our site by providing personal information to us for use for certain features, such as MyMcCormick, contests, to sign up for product testing, and to get information about career opportunities at McCormick. The information we collect may include, but is not limited to, name, contact information, the types of recipes you are interested in receiving from us, and information about your cooking habits. If you use our McCormickCorporation.com website, we may collect information such as your business contact information. We may on occasion collect personal information that you provide to third parties (such as information you provide in response to a McCormick advertisement that appears on another website). If we do collect personal information from third parties in such instances, we will treat that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**How We Use Your Personal Information.** We may use the information you provide on our website to send you periodic e-mail updates about our company, send you newsletters and recipes, to send you surveys or to notify you of special offers and promotions. You may opt out of receiving these communications at any time by clicking on the opt-out link located in each e-mail we send. If you have an online account with us, you may also opt out of receiving commercial e-mail communications by choosing to unsubscribe from your account preferences page. 

If you sign up to test products or participate in surveys on our website, then we will use your contact information to send you such products or surveys. 

If you provide us with your mailing address, we may use this information to send you special offers or promotions by mail. If you do not want to receive special offers or promotions by mail, please do not provide your mailing address. 

**Supplementation of Information.** We may on occasion supplement the personal information you provide to us with information from third party sources. We may also obtain publicly available data from third parties and use it to supplement our existing user database to better target our advertising and to provide pertinent offers in which we think you might be interested. 

**MyMcCormick.** As a member of MyMcCormick, you have the opportunity to share your thoughts with McCormick and other club members and save and organize your favorite McCormick recipes. If you choose to post information on our website, you should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these features. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit through these features on our website. 

Please note that we may use the information you post or store using your MyMcCormick account to send you targeted marketing offers. 

**Collection and Use of Your Non-Personal Information**

We also collect non-personal information − data in a form that does not permit direct association with any specific individual. We may collect, use, transfer, and disclose non-personal information for any purpose. The following are some examples of non-personal information that we collect and how we may use it:

We may collect information such as occupation, language, zip code, area code, cooking preferences, location, and the time zone so that we can better understand customer behavior and improve our products, services, and advertising.

We also may collect information regarding customer activities on our website. This information is aggregated and used to help us provide more useful information to our customers and to understand which parts of our website, products, and services are of most interest. Aggregated data is considered non-personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.

If we do combine non-personal information with personal information the combined information will be treated as personal information for as long as it remains combined.

**Cookies.** A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies on our websites. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance their experience on our site. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. 

If you reject cookies, you may still use our websites, but your ability to use some areas of our sites will be limited and we will not be able to provide you with the most convenient experience. 

**Log Files.** As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, the operating system you may be using (e.g., Windows XP or Mac OS), a date/time stamp of when you visited our site, and click-stream data. 

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze aggregate trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. 

We treat information collected by cookies and other technologies as non-personal information. However, to the extent that Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or similar identifiers are considered personal information by local law, we also treat these identifiers as personal information. Similarly, to the extent that non-personal information is combined with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.

**Disclosure of Personal Information to Third Parties.** At times McCormick may make certain personal information available to strategic partners that work with McCormick to provide products and services, or that help McCormick market to customers. Personal information will only be shared by McCormick to provide or improve our products, services and advertising; it will not be shared with third parties for their marketing purposes. McCormick may also share non-personal information or aggregate information about people who use our site to business partners and other third parties. 

**Disclosure of Personal Information to Services Providers.**   McCormick shares personal information with companies who provide services such as information processing, extending credit, fulfilling customer orders, delivering products to you, managing and enhancing customer data, providing customer service, assessing your interest in our products and services, and conducting customer research or satisfaction surveys. These companies are obligated to protect your information and may be located wherever McCormick operates.

**Compliance with Law.** Under certain circumstances, it is possible that personal information may be subject to disclosure pursuant to judicial or other legal requirements, such as warrants, subpoenas or court orders. McCormick will comply with any court order or other legal process and will provide your personal information if required in any legal proceeding. We also may release personal information when we believe in good faith that such release is appropriate to protect the rights, property or safety of McCormick our users, employees, or others. This may include, for example, exchanging information with other organizations for fraud protection and/or credit risk reduction. 

**Access to Your Personal Information.** You may view and change the personal information you have provided through the MyMcCormick feature of our website by accessing your MyMcCormick account profile online. To review and update your personal information, simply go to the Homepage. 

**Security.** McCormick's website employs appropriate security measures which are designed to prevent the loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of personal information. 

**Note to Parents.** We don't knowingly collect personal information from children. If you are under the age of 18, please do not use this site. Parents may have information related to their children deleted from our database and refuse to permit further collection or use of the child’s information. 

**Links to other sites.** This website may contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by McCormick. These sites may have their own terms and conditions, or no terms and conditions at all. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites, including those that enable you to apply for a position with our company, or those that may administer contests, sweepstakes or other promotions on our behalf. We provide links to third party websites as a convenience to our site visitors. These links are not intended as an endorsement of or referral to the linked websites. The linked websites have separate and independent privacy statements, notices and terms of use, which we recommend you read carefully. We do not have any control over such websites, and therefore we have no responsibility or liability for the manner in which the organizations that operate such linked websites may collect, use or disclose, secure and otherwise treat your personal information. By clicking on third party links, you are subject to the privacy practices of the third party website.

**Mobile Services.** McCormick offers a ‘Send to Phone’ recipe service (THE SERVICE). THE SERVICE offers text message recipe ingredients list delivered to your phone and mobile browser site access when requested from our online recipes pages. Depending on the length of the recipe ingredients list, more than one SMS text message may be sent. For a description of the Terms and Conditions for using the ‘Send to Phone’ recipe service, please see our Legal Notice. 

We may use information we receive as a result of your participation in THE SERVICE to send you targeted marketing offers. The information we may use includes but is not limited to your mobile device location or other account information. 

To opt out of receiving our recipe service, text "STOP" to 30123 from your mobile phone and we will unsubscribe you from our SMS text messaging service immediately. You will receive an OPT OUT confirmation message and will not receive any additional messages until you re-register on our website. To get help, email us at [mccormick_mobile@mccormick.com](mailto:mccormick_mobile@mccormick.com). From your mobile phone, you may request our contact information at any time by texting HELP to 30123. 

**How to contact us:** If you have any questions about this privacy policy, or the website overall, please contact us. 

For questions or comments regarding the McCormick.com website, please contact us at the following address: 

**Interactive Marketing  
Consumer Products Division  
McCormick & Co., Inc.  
24 Schilling Road, Suite 1  
Hunt Valley, MD 20131**  
or send us an [email](mailto:consumer_affairs@mccormick.com).

For questions or comments regarding the McCormickCorporation.com website, please contact us at the following address: 

**Corporate Communications  
McCormick & Company, Inc.  
24 Schilling Road, Suite 1  
Hunt Valley, MD 21031  
**or use our Contact form.
